You were brilliant, my knight.
[sniffles] Share in my glory,
for it was hard won.
[Xylo grunts softly]
I'd like to speak with you.
Something happened after
you defeated the Demon Lord,
and it directly concerns you.
I am not in the mood
for all that politicking crap.
Makes sense, but regardless,
I need you to hear me out.
♪
[seagulls squawking]
[indistinct chatter]
[MAN 1] Fresh off the hook!
[MAN 2] No. No more,
no more. Please.
[MAN 3]
Let's get moving already!
[door shuts]
[KIVIA] Long story short,
for the time being,
you and Goddess Teoritta
are officially on loan
to the Thirteenth Order
of Holy Knights.
We're "on loan"?
Like a piece of equipment?
The military and the Temple
are still locked in debate,
regarding the goddess'
extraordinary standing.
But your incredible feat
at the fortress,
it's causing a noticeable
sea change.
Xylo, consider this an order.
I want you
to keep protecting her.
If that's really
what you want...
[TEORITTA] Hm?
It's been ages
since we had a day off.
Take us off the front lines
for a change.
[KIVIA] That was
already the plan.
[XYLO] Huh?
I am deploying
your whole hero unit.
You are to protect
Goddess Teoritta.
For now, you will be
stationed here
in Port City Ioff.
[scoffs] In other words,
this place is more dangerous
than a battlefield.
Your assumption's
absolutely right.
There is a faction of heretics
who were expelled
from the Temple,
and they refuse to accept
a new goddess.
They've joined forces with
a religious order of assassins.
-They are plotting to kill--
-[XYLO] Enough, tell me later.
[TEORITTA] My knight!
It is your sacred duty
to protect me!
Alongside our band of heroes,
we shall savor a moment
of respite!
[chuckles]
[paper rustling]
[Teoritta snores]
-[door slams open]
-[Teoritta gasps]
[XYLO] Hm.
♪
[grunts softly]
[Teoritta grunts softly]
Xylo, rumor has it
you dealt some nasty blows
to the Blight.
Good to see you too, Jayce.
Also I heard about those
three Demon Lords
you erased from existence,
though it sounded like
Dotta and Norgalle
did all the heavy lifting.
I guess Iblis might be
an exception.
Suppose I can accept
that was you.
Meanwhile, I killed two of 'em!
[chuckles] Are you sure
about that number?
Wasn't Rhyno
on the western front with you?
He got nailed
for insubordination.
He'll be locked up a long while.
They're housing a penal hero
in a prison cell?
Just admit it. I took out two
while you only managed
to kill one.
I'm the winner
and you're the loser!
Still your wicked tongue!
You are addressing
my knight, knave!
I shall not allow you
to malign him so!
Guessing you're the goddess?
I hear that thief Dotta
found you.
Must be comforting having
a puny kid for a bodyguard.
[Teoritta grunts] The sheer
insolence on display!
Never have I been subject
to such flagrant disrespect!
Easy. Getting angry
won't stop him.
And Dotta didn't find her,
he stole the casket she was in
from the Holy Knights.
[scoffs] I don't see
a big difference.
Like I give a damn
about law and order.
You lost. Time to pony up.
Neely will sulk
if I make her wait.
[Xylo grunts]
[XYLO] Give my regards to Neely.
[Jayce chuckles]
[door slams shut]
My goodness, what is the matter
with that man?
Settle yourself.
That's our unit's dragoon,
Jayce.
He's a fool who grew
and sold illegal substances.
Drugs strong enough
to help dragons.
He was made a hero for that?
[XYLO] That and insurrection.
They say he revolted
against the military
in attempt
to free their dragons.
Uprisings like that
don't usually last a full day,
but Jayce is from
a powerful noble family
and dragons love him.
It escalated beyond reason
and was dubbed
"Jayce's Revolt."
So I was correct
in my prior assessment
that hero types
are most eccentric.
Hello.
♪
-[thumps]
-[Xylo grunts]
[grunts] Please,
let us work through this
like rational adults!
With words!
[screams]
It was for your benefit!
Even you have to admit
things would have ended up
a whole lot worse
if the Mastibolt cavalry
hadn't shown up when they did!
I know, and that's why
I'm only gonna hit you twice.
No, Xylo! This is not the time
for violence!
Of course it is.
The little rat is keeping
something from us.
Me? I wouldn't dream of it!
Oh, there is one little thing.
Frenci did ask
to speak with you.
Said she'd murder me
if I didn't make it happen
right away.
I fear my hands are tied.
This Frenci, who might she be?
A noble and my former fiancée.
[TEORITTA] Huh?
♪
Xylo, you are such a mess.
[Teoritta grunts softly]
Why are you acting strangely?
Sit down this instant.
How disappointing
that you haven't improved
in the slightest.
You were on the level
of a fly before,
now a caterpillar.
It's quite grave.
[Xylo sighs]
It wouldn't kill you
to be less insulting
with your comparisons.
Oh, dear.
Do flat-landers consider
pure fact an insult?
I was merely encouraging you
to behave in a manner
that befits a future member
of the Mastibolt family.
Chalk it up
to a cultural difference.
I'll try to remember that.
It was truly not my intention
to cause offense.
Tell me, is she
the goddess in question?
[XYLO] Don't glare.
You'll scare her.
[TEORITTA] I am not afraid
of her whatsoever!
Goddesses have no need of fear!
Indeed. And I'm not glaring,
simply looking.
You are called "Frenci,"
are you not?
Speak truthfully.
What are you to my noble knight?
My former fiancée,
-like I told you.
-[Teoritta grunts]
"Former" is inaccurate.
The oath that binds us
remains intact, Xylo.
Have you just conveniently
forgotten that I'm a hero now?
-We're not allowed to be wed.
-[TEORITTA] Mm-hmm.
Legally, I'm not even considered
an actual human anymore.
Heed my words, Frenci.
This man is a hero as well as
my chosen knight,
and he has irrevocably sworn
to spend
the remainder of his days
in reverent adulation of me!
As such, I must
regretfully shatter your dream.
He cannot marry you!
Not again. A curious creature
has taken a liking to you.
This reminds me
of back when my father's
long-eared armadillo
was smitten with you.
Meanwhile, all you got
were scratches.
[FRENCI] That was only because
a western merchant--
Halt! Injustice!
Recounting your shared history
in my presence?
And surely you realize
it is the height of disrespect
to compare a goddess
to a lowly armadillo!
[FRENCI] As I was saying,
our oath remains, and as such,
I am currently attempting
to arrange a pardon for you.
You are? But that's not--
[FRENCI] I will remain
in this city for a while yet,
for good reason.
I refuse to return home
until I've located
the Demon Blight.
[Teoritta gasps]
[XYLO] What do you mean?
[FRENCI] Precisely what I said.
About a month ago,
the night-gaunt chiefs and I
embarked on special maneuvers
to track down a Demon Blight.
A few days ago,
their entire force vanished
somewhere near this town.
[XYLO] Vanished?
That's right.
It was Demon Blight Number 59,
Spriggan, and I have a theory.
It masquerades as human.
Demon Lords can appear human?
Is that so?
It's a rare trait even among
Demon Lords.
Annoying. What a damn headache.
[FRENCI] It's possible it has
infiltrated the city by now.
Tread carefully.
The creature
has already laid waste
to one of our territories.
Anyhow, this concludes
our discussion.
May I ask who has been
eavesdropping in the corner?
Sorry, I have to supervise.
It's a rule.
I must ensure there isn't
any suspicious activity.
I see. Farewell then.
I suggest you come up
with a better excuse next time.
[TEORITTA]
I deeply desire to indulge!
Venetim and Dotta
told me about it.
The west and north sides
of the city
are filled with stalls
selling rare goods,
and every bite of food
is completely free!
It's only free for someone
with sticky fingers like Dotta.
We're not going sightseeing,
and that's final.
We're here for a purpose,
to lure out
those Temple heretics
who are after you,
and arrest them.
Verily, I am well-aware
of your noble plan
to protect your goddess!
[sighs] Listen carefully.
The Holy Sword is our secret.
If those Galtuile bastards
find out,
our lives will get a lot harder.
There is no need to fret!
For I am a goddess, after all.
I know just what to do!
[Xylo sighs]
I'll join you two
on your excursion.
I'm prepared to be
the goddess' sword and shield,
if need be.
[Teoritta groans]
[XYLO] It's settled.
I wonder who else
we should bring along.
[Venetim humming]
[XYLO] Venetim's worthless
as a bodyguard.
I can't let Dotta loose in town
unless I tie his hands
behind his back.
His Majesty
would probably insist
we act as his royal guard.
-As for Tatsuya...
-[birds chirping]
[XYLO]... that's a bad idea.
Hate to say it,
we're low on options.
♪
[hammering]
-[hammering continues]
-[Jayce grunting]
These morons
honestly expect me
to keep Neely in this dump?
Bastards.
The least they can do
is give her enough room
to spread her wings and tail.
I agree, it is critical.
By the way, I have
important commander work
that needs tending to,
so I'll just take my leave.
Who's the most powerful force
in this entire unit?
Without question,
it's you and Neely.
In that case, do your part
to keep her in prime condition,
and shut your mouth, conman.
Hold on a little longer, Neely.
I'll have a nice bed ready
for you soon.
[Neely huffs]
Hm? [chuckles] Don't worry
about the other dragons,
I was simply measuring them
out of curiosity,
and I didn't take a peek
under any of their wings.
You know,
I wouldn't dare do that.
Believe me.
[Neely growls softly]
[JAYCE]
I've never lied to you...
This could go on for forever.
[VENETIM] I need some help here!
-[crashing]
-[Venetim yelps]
Looks like we're down
to our last option.
-[bell tolling]
-[indistinct chatter]
[TSAV] Take my word for it, bro,
those guys
are the absolute worst!
Gwen Mohsa calls itself
a "religious order."
I know they raised me and all,
but a fact is still a fact.
Even I could always tell
they were pure evil.
I'm talkin' human sacrifice,
offering up kids
to the goddesses.
And don't get me started
on "Holy Communion,"
-which meant--
-Enough already.
[TSAV] Fine.
If he's going
to prattle on like that,
why did we even
bother with disguises?
On that subject...
[MAN] Hey, wait, wait!
Come back!
-[XYLO] Well done.
-[KIVIA] Uh?
Brilliant choice
to dress as a man.
It's the perfect disguise.
[Kivia grunts softly]
[TEORITTA] Come hither, Xylo!
I wish for us to purchase
a keepsake,
in commemoration.
[XYLO] Of what, exactly?
The very first time
a great goddess
and her equally great knight
blessed these city streets
with their presence.
I should have known.
Well, what do you want?
I insist that we make
our selection together!
After all, it is a prize
for both of us. [chuckles]
♪
[indistinct chatter]
Perhaps this fabric
would suffice.
Behold how it shimmers
when held in the light!
I'm guessing that was
brought here from the west,
across Korio Bay.
They have lots of unique wares.
[TEORITTA] Look, a bracelet!
I dare say that piece
is worthy of a goddess.
It looks like jade.
You could buy a house
for the same price.
We'd better keep Dotta far away.
I did not inquire
about the price.
And this matter
does not concern Dotta. Hmph!
Hey, Tsav, what would you do
if you were the assassin?
Um, I'd probably mix in
with the crowd,
then a little quick slash
as I walked past?
Listen well!
Your goddess hereby decrees
that you should be giving
your full attention
to picking out our keepsake!
[XYLO] Understood.
♪
[XYLO] Finally,
something I can appreciate.
Have you chosen?
Never mind.
It's dangerous
to give children weapons.
Utter nonsense!
You shall instruct me.
Select my blade!
Let's go with...
[Xylo grunts softly]
This one here.
[Teoritta exclaims]
How magnificent.
It is beautiful.
We'll purchase the knife.
And that, too.
You take scrip?
[Xylo grunts]
It's yours. And keep it
at the ready.
I shall.
[♪ tense music playing]
-[Teoritta gasps]
-[Kivia grunts]
-[assassin screaming]
-[crowd gasping]
[chokes]
[woman whimpers]
[woman screams]
[Teoritta gasps softly]
Ooh, lookie here. Spoils of war.
Xylo, switch
to the alternate route!
Got it. Let's get moving.
Does that mean
the battle is afoot?
[XYLO] Afraid so.
We'll call this sightseeing.
What the hell's going on here?
Where are all the Holy Knights?
This is not good.
Something must have happened
to them all.
Don't worry. Those guys weren't
religious-order assassins,
and it was so obvious
they didn't have
any real training
under their belts.
Stay sharp.
For all we know, they could be
allies of the Demon Blight.
[Xylo exhales] Coexisters.
[KIVIA] Regardless,
it's someone who benefits
from the goddess' death.
I didn't think they had
infiltrated the military.
[Tsav gasps]
[Tsav grunts]
Freaky! Stay back!
[Tsav gasps]
[Tsav grunts]
Who the hell are you?
[Tsav pants]
[TSAV] She's got some
filthy tricks, bro.
Real nasty.
This pain is brutal!
They have come.
What to do?
Remain here.
We'll end this quickly.
♪
[assassin grunts]
-[Kivia grunts]
-[XYLO] Stay back.
[both grunts]
[grunts] A seal compound?
Surprise.
Can you fight?
Who do you think
you're talking to?
Stay silent and on your guard.
[Xylo grunts]
[MAN] That is quite enough,
Shiji Bau.
You're up against
the penal hero
who is pacted with a goddess.
Your chances of victory
are one in a thousand.
It is time to withdraw.
Are you even
listening to me, Shiji Bau?
You amateur,
think before you speak.
You cannot just go around
saying our names.
Got it, Boojum?
Is that so?
I truly had no idea.
I've yet to learn
the fine details of the trade.
Given your experience, I hope
you'll continue to teach me--
Please hurry up, sir!
Before the Holy Knights
show up!
[BOOJUM] Be quiet.
Can you not tell
that I am talking to someone?
It's rather rude to interrupt,
don't you see?
-[grunts]
-[Teoritta gasps]
Remember, we were told to avoid
unnecessary casualties.
[BOOJUM] Casualties?
Ah, but I didn't kill him.
That would be uncouth.
You ripped his jaw clean off.
There is something wrong
with you.
That much is apparent.
Kivia!
[KIVIA] Niskeph!
[Shiji Bau grunts]
[BOOJUM] Refrain from using
lightning staves.
Getting shot in the back...
stings.
[Xylo grunts]
Are you Xylo Forbartz?
As in the infamous penal hero?
Who's asking?
I think she called you "Boojum"?
Did you escape a circus troupe?
[BOOJUM] I did not.
You're quite the exceptional
knife-thrower, though.
Perhaps you should have
joined a circus troupe.
I did, and for three years
to boot.
My specialty was
the flying trapeze.
Is that so?
That explains it.
I can assure you without even
a sliver of exaggeration
that you're the best
I've ever seen.
You have my respect.
Seriously, just stop talking.
Never willingly volunteer
information.
A solid point.
I am pleased to say
I'm learning a lot
from you today.
We're in a real predicament
here, guys.
That tricksy broad?
She just so happens to be
a world-famous adventurer.
I bet she has
an even better kill rate
on her hits than you do.
Probably! But my numbers
would be through the roof,
if I weren't
such a big old softie.
[Teoritta panting]
Is it time?
Shall I call down
a rain of swords?
You'd better not.
Would it not be prudent
to do so?
I know how painful it is
for a goddess to harm a human.
And I refuse to do that to you.
That is true,
yet something is amiss.
I have the strangest feeling
that he...
-[whooshing]
-Look up, bro! Incoming!
Perfect. Right on cue.
[Teoritta gasps]
[assassins screaming]
[assassin screams] Help me.
[Teoritta gasps]
Well?
We came to this dingy place
like you asked.
Now show Neely some gratitude.
Of course. Thank you, Neely.
Thanks, Big Sis Neely!
Good work!
[Neely huffs]
Attagirl! We don't deserve
your kindness.
And I promise we'll have
a day off real soon.
We'll go and fly
over the sea tomorrow.
-[Neely grunts]
-[Jayce exclaims]
[BOOJUM] How curious.
Seems dragon flames
are difficult to endure.
[Xylo gasps]
[BOOJUM] I do not have
enough blood.
This was informative.
I will be taking my leave now.
Farewell.
[Kivia grunts softly]
[Tsav grunts]
What's that guy's deal?
No way he should have survived
Neely's flame.
Teoritta,
right before
you were interrupted,
what were you saying
about that man?
It is most difficult
to put it to words.
I found that,
for some strange reason,
I felt surprisingly unhesitant
when faced with the notion
of attacking him.
It is possible,
the man we just fought,
was Demon Lord Spriggan.
[♪ closing theme song playing]